http://williamgrimes.xyz/ n

SUMMARY

William Grimes

Data Scientist, with two years experience delivering commercial data science projects working with the World Economic Forum, Netherlands' Transportation Ministry, and the London Fire Brigade. Hold a PhD in Bioinformatics, and a MSc in Computer Science, with over eight years programming experience. Dedicated to applying machine learning to solve problems with social impact, and particularly interested in imaging, geospatial data, and natural language processing.

Professional EXPERIENCE

Numerico Technologies

Data Scientist and Engineer

Feb 2018 – present

Data Scientist and software-engineer.

→ Developed and deployed a live system for the Netherlands Rijkswaterstaat transportation ministry using neural networks to predict the likelihood of road traffic accidents along Dutch highways.

Data Science for Social Good (DSSG)

Data Scientist and Mentor

Jun 2017 - Jan 2018

DSSG Europe 2017 member and DSSG 2018 technical mentor.

→ Developed an open-source fishing risk tool combining vessel tracking data with satellite imagery, using a random forest to score vessels according to likelihood of illegal fishing behaviours. Project code is available here: https://github.com/DSSG2017/wef_oceans

ASI Data Science / London Fire Brigade

Data Science Consultant

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

Fellowship programme in commercial data science for researchers with strong analytic background. → In house consultant with the London Fire Brigade, implementing topic modelling methods to classify corpus of 37,000 fire incident reports. Revealed previously unknown incident types, and visualised results. Project code: https://github.com/williamgrimes/london_fire_brigade

Laboratory for Molecular Cell Biology (LMCB)

PhD Student

Sep 2013 - Nov 2016

Joint scholarship at LMCB and A*STAR Bioinformatics Institute, Singapore.

→ Applied machine learning techniques and segmented endothelial cell phenotypes in high-throughput microscopy assays. Analysed over 5TB of data with a detection accuracy of 82%.

National Institute of Informatics (国立情報学研究所)

International Internship Programme

Jun 2013 - Sep 2016

→ Developed Java-based annotation software which assisted in classifying developmental phenotypes in μ CT images of mutant mice

EDUCATION

University College London

PhD Bioinformatics

Sep 2013 - Nov 2016

→ Thesis: Image processing and analysis methods in quantitative endothelial cell biology

University College London

MSc Computer Science

Sep 2012 - Sep 2013

→ Awarded Aardvark Scholarship 2012

Durham University

BSc Natural Sciences – Physics and Geophysics

 $\mathbf{Sep}\ \mathbf{2009} - \mathbf{Sep}\ \mathbf{2012}$

SKILLS / **KEYWORDS**

Programming: Python, R, Java, Matlab, SQL, Solidity, Bash and utils (sed, awk, grep)

Machine Learning: regression, decision trees, ensembles, SVM, neural networks, deep learning Libraries: NumPy, pandas, SciPy, scikit-learn, scikit-image, OpenCV, Keras, theano, tensorflow

Visualisation: matplotlib, bokeh, plotly, ggplot, Tableau

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server

Front-end: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Semantic UI, Jekyll Misc: Amazon Web Services, Azure, Docker, Git, Jupyter Notebooks, IATFX, UNIX